Hotel Guests Check In...But They Don't Check Out!
Tower of Terror is a comedy, family, horror film directed by D.J. MacHale.
A disgraced reporter investigates an abandoned luxury hotel where five
people mysteriously disappeared sixty years earlier.
Buzzy Crocker, played by Steve Guttenberg.
Anna Petterson, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Jill Perry, played by Nia Peeples.
Chris 'Q' Todd, played by Michael McShane.
Abigail Gregory, played by Amzie Strickland.
Claire Poulet, played by Melora Hardin.
The Twilight Zone Tower of Terror, or simply Tower of Terror, is a series of similar accelerated drop tower dark rides located at
Disney's Hollywood Studios, Tokyo DisneySea, Walt Disney Studios Park, and formerly located at Disney California Adventure.
The attraction is inspired by Rod Serling's anthology television series, The Twilight Zone, and
takes place in the fictional "Hollywood Tower Hotel" in Hollywood, California.
The Tokyo version features an original storyline not related to The
Twilight Zone and takes place in the fictional "Hotel Hightower".
All versions of the attraction place riders in a seemingly ordinary hotel elevator, and present a fictional backstory in which people
have mysteriously disappeared from the elevator under the influence of a supernatural element many years previously.
The original version of the attraction opened at Disney's Hollywood Studios,
then named Disney-MGM Studios, at Walt Disney World in July 1994.
A decade later, Disney began plans to add similar versions of the attraction to their newest parks at
the Disneyland Resort in California, Tokyo Disney Resort in Japan, and Disneyland Paris.
In California and Paris, Disney sought to use the popular attraction to boost
attendance at the respective resorts' struggling new theme parks.
The California and Tokyo versions of Tower of Terror opened in 2004 and 2006, respectively,
while financial problems delayed the opening of the Paris version until 2007.
The California version closed in January 2017 and was replaced by Guardians of the Galaxy – Mission:
Breakout!, which was later incorporated into the adjacent Avengers Campus in 2021.
The Tower of Terror buildings are among the tallest
structures found at their respective Disney resorts.
At 199 feet (60.7 m), the Florida version is the second tallest attraction at the Walt Disney World Resort,
with only Expedition Everest at Disney's Animal Kingdom being taller by 0.5 feet (0.2 m).
After its retheme, the 183-foot (55.8 m) structure at the Disneyland Resort is still the tallest
building on the property, as well as one of the tallest buildings in Anaheim.
At Disneyland Paris, it is the second tallest attraction.
The film explores themes of hotel, halloween, hollywood, ghost, elevator.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.